Finding Aid for the The Peter Taylor Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Series II. Writings
  - Short Stories – Unpublished
    - “Two Women.” Typescript, p. 1-9, with holograph corrections. (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - “Two Women.” Typescript (untitled), p. 1-9, with holograph corrections. (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - “The Waiting Room.” Typescript, p. 1-18, with holograph corrections. Collections (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Collections
    - *The Typescript for Taylor’s The Old Forest And Other Stories includes the following:, The Gift of the Prodigal The Old Forest Promise of Rain Bad Dreams A Friend and Protector A Walled Garden Allegiance The Little Cousins A Long Fourth Rain in the Heart Porte-Cochere The Scoutmaster Two Ladies in Retirement The Death of a Kinsman
    - The Old Forest And Other Stories. Typescript, p. 1-456, of the setting copy used by Doubleday & Company, Inc. to prepare this book. (1 of 14) (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - The Old Forest And Other Stories. (2 of 14) (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - The Old Forest And Other Stories. (3 of 14) (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - The Old Forest And Other Stories. (4 of 14) (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - The Old Forest And Other Stories. (5 of 14) (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - The Old Forest And Other Stories. (6 of 14) (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - The Old Forest And Other Stories. (7 of 14) (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - The Old Forest And Other Stories. (8 of 14) (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - The Old Forest And Other Stories. (9 of 14) (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - The Old Forest And Other Stories. (10 of 14) (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - The Old Forest And Other Stories. (11 of 14) (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - The Old Forest And Other Stories. (12 of 14) (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - The Old Forest And Other Stories. (13 of 14) (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - The Old Forest And Other Stories. (14 of 14) (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - The Old Forest And Other Stories. Style Sheet (3 p.) and character list (1 p.) completed by copy editor, Robert Brown. Style sheet dated 6-13-1984. Also 1 p. preprinted form of accented characters, symbols, etc. available in the font being used to set the copy. (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - The Old Forest And Other Stories. Page proofs, 1-360, with holograph corrections. (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Novels
    - A Summons To Memphis. Typescript notes, 2 p. (1 a photocopy). (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - A Summons To Memphis. Typescript fragment (titled “Old Enemies”), p. 1-2, of broken line prose with holograph corrections. (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - A Summons To Memphis. Typescript fragment (untitled), p. 25-26, of broken line prose with holograph corrections. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - A Summons To Memphis. Parts of various drafts (includes variant titles listed below), most in broken line prose and heavily annotated, detailed as follows: Typescript, p. -, 2-4, - (“Old Enemies”), 3-5, 5, 4a, 7, 6, 2-5, 9, 4-6, 8-11, 6, 6, - (“Old Enemies”), 2-3, 6, 2-3, 2-5, - (“The Dueling Ground”), 2, 5, 3, 2, - (“The One That Got Away”), 2, 6-8, - (“O, Blue-Eyed Banditti!”), 2-14, 3, 2, 2, 2, - (“The Garden District”), - (“The Blue-Eyed Banditti”), - (“A Modest House In Memphis Proper” crossed out and “The Fatality” written over it), 15, 2; Holograph notes (5 p.); Typescript, p. 1-2. (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - A Summons To Memphis. Typescript fragment (untitled), p. 78-103, in broken line prose with holograph corrections. (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - A Summons To Memphis. Typescript fragment (titled “The Notebooks” – also has “The Father Figure” and “The Father Image” written at head), p.1-12, holograph corrections. (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - A Summons To Memphis. Photocopy of typescript (titled “The Notebooks”), p. 1-3, with holograph corrections. (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - A Summons To Memphis. Photocopy of typescript (titled “The Notebooks”), p.1-30, 1-30. (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - A Summons To Memphis. Various typescript fragments (includes variant titles listed below), in part photocopies, in both broken line prose and traditional prose, with holograph corrections. p. 78-103, 15-19, 78-103, 36-37, 39-52, 54, 53a, 53, 55-57, 20-24, 1-14, 9-13, 29-48, 18, 23-24, 49, 74a, 74c, 1-180 (title “The Trail of Tears” has been crossed out and above it appears “A Summons Home” and “A Summons to Memphis.” Another title at the left is “The Removal.” There are also subtitles “Being the Notebooks of an Old Bachelor Son & Brother” and “Notebooks of an Unmarried Son.”) (Box 9, Folder 9-20)
    - A Summons To Memphis. Various typescript fragments, in part photocopies, in both broken line prose and traditional prose, with holograph corrections, detailed as follows: 1 p. holograph notes, p. 136, 171, 177, 178, 178, 25, 4-8, 39, 36-38, 26-27, 7-13, 9-20, 40-43, 2-4, 15, 2, 35, 55, 3 p. holograph notes (1 p. titled “Poetry of Character and Context,” 1p. titled “Reunion at Owl Mountain”), 22, 26-29, 21, 6, 5, 4, 3, 2, 1, 1-3, 1-10, 31, 30, 32-35, 44-49, 38, 19, 17-18, 14-16, 46, 8-9, 47, 45, 4, 48-58, 36, 2-5, 41-44, 29, 25, 25, 26-34, 20-24, 49-55, 1, 5-7, 10-14, 14, 5-13, 15-35, 1-3, 5, 54, 56-60, 19-31, 20-24, 61-64, 73, 1-18, 50-58, 62, 59, 60-72. (Box 9, Folder 21-31)
    - A Summons To Memphis. Various typescript fragments, in part photocopies, in both broken line prose and traditional prose, with holograph corrections, detailed as follows: 1-53 [“The Trail of Tears” and “A Summons To Memphis” crossed out and replaced with “A Summons Home”, other titles, subtitles difficult to read], 55-71, 74, 72, 73, 75-89, 102-177. (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
    - A Summons To Memphis. Photocopy of typescript fragment, p. 4-30, some holograph corrections. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - A Summons To Memphis. Photocopy of typescript fragment, p. 56, 56a, 56b, some holograph corrections. (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - A Summons To Memphis. Photocopy of typescript fragment, p. 103. (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - A Summons To Memphis. Holograph notes, 7 p., typescript fragment p. 1777a-180, “Charlottesville October 14, 1985” at end of manuscript. (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - A Summons To Memphis. Photocopy of typescript, p. 1-219, an early setting copy. “Gainesville, January 8, 1986” at end of manuscript. (Box 10, Folder 7-9)
    - A Summons To Memphis. Photocopy of typescript, p. 71-218, setting copy. “Gainesville, January 8, 1986” at end of manuscript. (Box 10, Folder 10-11)
    - A Summons To Memphis. Page proofs, p. 1-209, marked “Set 2, Untouched.” Also 2 other loose pages. (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - A Summons To Memphis. Page proofs, p. 1-212, with more setting notes and title page mock-up. (Box 10, Folder 13-15)
    - A Summons To Memphis. Page proofs, p. 1-209, in 7 gatherings of 16 leaves each, with further setting notes. (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - A Summons To Memphis. Photocopy of design for dust jacket. (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - A Summons To Memphis. List of persons to whom A Summons To Memphis was sent. (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - A Woman of Means. Galleys dated September 13, 1983, p. 1-90, with editor’s corrections. (1984-second edition published by Frederic C. Beil.) (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Plays – Published
    - Arson. Photocopy of typescript, p. 1-15, dated “February 10, 1971” – probably an earlier version. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Arson. Typescript, p. 1-17, with holograph corrections. Marked “duplicate.” (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Arson. Photocopy of typescript, p. 1-2, 4-33. (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - A Father And A Son. Photocopy of typescript, p.1-10, with holograph corrections. Probably an early version. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - A Father And A Son. Photocopy of typescript, p.1-14, with holograph corrections. Signed by Peter Taylor. Also 1 page typescript describing opening of play. (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - A Father And A Son. Photocopy of typescript (untitled), p.3-14, same version as in File 10 above. (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - A Stand In The Mountains. Typescript fragment (untitled), p. 1-4, 1-4, also 1 p. holograph, partially broken line prose, with holograph annotations. Possibly an early version of what became a play. (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - A Stand In The Mountains. Typescript fragment (untitled), p. 1-2, 3-4, 3-5, 5-9, with holograph corrections, also 2 holograph pages. Possibly an early version of what became a play. (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - A Stand In The Mountains. Typescript fragment, p. 1-2 with holograph corrections, also 1 holograph page. An early broken line prose version. (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - A Stand In The Mountains. Typescript fragment (also titled “The Girl From Forked Deer”), p. 1, 1, 2, 1 in broken line prose with holograph corrections. (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - A Stand In The Mountains. 8 holograph pages, typescript fragment p. 1-2 in play format with holograph corrections. (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - A Stand In The Mountains. 3 holograph pages of Scene 3. (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - A Stand In The Mountains. Typescript fragment, p. 3-15, from Scene 3, with holograph corrections. (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - A Stand In The Mountains. Typescript fragment, p. 2-6 (marked “insert page 239”), p. 241 (marked “new ending to Scene IV”). (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - The Sweethearts. Typescript (titled “The Settee”), p. 1-10, 13-15, 14, 11-13, with holograph corrections. (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - The Sweethearts. Typescript, p. 1-14, with holograph corrections. (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - The Sweethearts. Photocopy of typescript, p. 1-23. (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Three Ghost Plays (Includes Two Images, A Father And A Son and Missing Person ). Typescript, p. 1-9, 1-7, 1-13, 19 with holograph corrections. (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Three Ghost Plays (Includes Two Images, A Father And A Son and Missing Person ). Photocopy of typescript, p. 1-13, 1-10, 1-19, with holograph corrections. (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Two Images. Photocopy of typescript, p. 2-13, with holograph corrections. (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - A Voice Through The Door. Typescript (also titled “A Voice At The Door” and “An Old Woman’s Dream”), p. 1-14, with holograph corrections, dated “January 18, 1971.” (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - A Voice Through The Door. Typescript, p. 1-14, with holograph corrections. Marked “duplicate.” (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - A Voice Through The Door. Photocopy of typescript, p. 1-14, with holograph corrections. (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - A Voice Through The Door. Photocopy of typescript, p. 1-26. (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - The Whistler. Typescript, p. 1-15, with holograph corrections. (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Plays – Unpublished
    - “From Five To Eight.” Typescript fragment, p. 1-5, 7-9, 1-6, with holograph corrections. (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Poems – Published
    - “His Other Life.” Typescript, p. 1-2, with holograph corrections. Signed by Peter Taylor. (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Poems – Unpublished
    - “A Didactic Poem for R.T.S.L. With The Proper Accoutrements” 1 page typescript, dated 1939. (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Essays
    - “Tennessee Caravan.” Typescript, p. 1-16, with holograph corrections. “Charlottesville, June 18, 1985” at end of manuscript. (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - “Tennessee Caravan.” Galleys, p. 5-10, with holograph corrections. (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Reviews
    - “The Assumptions of the Game.” Review of The Fathers by Allen Tate, pages 21-22 from Hika (February, 1939). (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Speeches
    - “Literature, Sewanee, and the World.” Photocopy of typescript, p. 1-9, dated “October 10, 1972.” Printed pamphlet of the essay, the Founders’ Day Address 1972; p. 3-4 of The Sewanee News for December, 1972 with excerpts from the address. (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Untitled. First lines “What is a novel? What is a story? What is a poem? What even is a play?” Typescript, p. 1-3, 1-5, with holograph corrections. (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Untitled. First lines “What is a novel? What is a story? What is a poem? What even is a play?” Typescript, p. 1-9, with holograph corrections. (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Untitled. Introduces a reading by Allen Tate, 1 page typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Tributes
    - “R.T.S. Lowell.” Typescript, p. 1-4, 1-2, also typescript of “The Dead Poets” from History. (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - “R.T.S. Lowell.” Typescript, p. 1-6, with holograph corrections. “Charlottesville, November 25, 1977” at end of manuscript. (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - “Robert Traill Spence Lowell.” Photocopy of typescript, p. 1-7. “Charlottesville, November 25, 1977” at end of manuscript. (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - Notes & Fragments
    - Holograph fragments on notebook paper, 43 p., appear to be beginnings of stories, plays, etc. Not all pieces are titled, but some are titled as follows: (Box 12, Folder 1)
      “A Winter Wedding” “A Scene From Modern Life”
      “The Money” “Merrypoint Drive”
      “You’re In Love” “A Man Of Imagination”
      “By Appointment” “Tears”
      “The Brothers Harrison” “The End of Something”
      “Three Friends” “Words, Words, Words...”
      “A Midnight Soliloquy” “At Bonassola”
      “Rooming Houses” “The Working Rich”
      “How To Come Home And Like It” “Sailing From Genoa”
      “The Partisans” “The Professor’s Son”
      “Emmaline”
    - Spiral bound notebook with holograph drafts, 26 pages, of stories, plays, etc. Cover of notebook labeled “Lives,” “Once Removed”, “Book I, The Pilgrim Sons.” Following titles included inside:, “Radicalized” or “The Incorruptible”, another title illegible (appears to be early draft of the play “Arson”, dated February 10, 1971.) Untitled fragment, appears to be part of “A Stand In The Mountains” “Truth” “The Party” “Family Style” or “The Thousand Years” “The Quick And The Dead” or “Jehovah’s Daughter” (appears to be an early draft of the play “A Voice Through The Door”, dated January 16, 1971.) (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Holograph and typescript drafts and fragments, 19 pages, including the following titles:, “The Death of Conway Thompson” “The Hand of Emma Sue” “A Nashville Lady Living at Rapallo” “A Lady Living at Rapallo” (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - 1 p. holograph draft in spiral notebook, untitled. (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - 1 p. typescript draft with holograph notes titled “The Piedmontese” (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - 1 p. holograph draft titled “Washington” (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - 1 p. holograph draft titled “Apres Moi” (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - 4 p. typescript drafts, titled:, “A Rope from Hell” “At The Market” “In An Unnamed City” (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - 16 p. holograph drafts and fragments, including the following titles:, “Growth” “A Success Story” “The Age of Annie Sue” (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - 5 p. holograph notes, appear to be autobiographical, possibly concerning Robert Lowell. Partially in the form of a journal. (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Spiral bound notebook titled “Generations” on the cover. 75 p. holograph drafts (among which are scattered drafts of letters), including the following titles:, “The Young Poet” “The Girl From Forked Deer” (possibly an early version of “A Stand In The Mountains”) “Generations”, “New Friends & Old Enemies”, “Two Sisters” (possibly an early version of A Summons To Memphis) “Grandfather” “The Other Women in Washington” “The Best of the Worst” or “That Summer” (possibly an early version of A Summons To Memphis ) “A Family Cortege” or “Man Power, Woman Power” “Old Enemies” (possibly an early version of A Summons To Memphis) “The World Didn’t End, After All, At Appomatox (sic)” “In Office” “Life in the Same House” “The Garden District” (possibly an early version of A Summons To Memphis) “Vengeance” “A Converstion Between My Father & Grandfather In Heaven” -(?) “The Gift of the Prodigal and Other Stories” (list of titles for collection) “Youth” “The Old Enemy” or “The One That Got Away” (possibly an early version of A Summons To Memphis ) (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - 6 p. holograph and typescript drafts with note labeled “miscellaneous episodes and paragraphs” in Taylor’s hand. One title “Impressions” included. (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Spiral bound notebook, 7 p. holograph drafts of “A Stand In The Mountains” and “The Girl From Forked Deer.” Also includes draft of a letter. (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - 8 p. holograph notes. (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - 9 p. holograph drafts, variously titled “Gathering For The Funeral”, “The Elect”, “The Battles”, “After the Election”, “In The Hospital Waiting Room”, initialed by Taylor and dated November 28, 1966. Also what appears to be a draft of “Randall Jarrell” for Randall Jarrell, 1914-1965. (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - 16 p. holograph drafts, dated July 11, 1968. (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - 12 p. holograph drafts, dated July 11, 1968. (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Spiral bound notebooks with holograph drafts of “The Gift of the Prodigal” (“Yaddo, 8-2-80”), “Mixed Feelings”, “A Peripheral Person”, “An Old Husband’s Lovesong”, “Children”, “Now It’s All Different”, “Now It’s Not Like That”, “Two Journeys To Memphis” and “Notebooks of a Dutiful Son & Brother” (possibly early versions of A Summons To Memphis ), “A Posthumous Portrait”, “Memories of a Family Man”, “Words, Words, Words,” also drafts of letters and recommendations scattered throughout. (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - 42 p. holograph drafts, including titles “A Stranger”, “The Hand of Annie Sue”, “A Compromise”, “Deconsecration”, “The Old Religion”, “In The Hospital Waiting Room”, “Our Old Ones”, (signed and dated June 1, 1967). (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Spiral bound notebook of holograph drafts, 50p., with various titles “Isn’t It Wonderful?”, “Receipt, Price Paid”, “Five Miles From Home”, “Journal”, “Parting of the Ways.” Appears to include parts of both “The Old Forest” and A Summons To Memphis. (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - 1 p. typescript with holograph corrections, numbered as page 12. (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - 1 p. typescript with holograph corrections re: “the artist”. (Box 12, Folder 22)
- Series III. Literary Career
  - Awards
    - Membership Certificate, National Istitute of Arts And Letters, 1969. Clippings re: Pulitzer, Ritz-Hemingway Prizes, 1987. (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Contracts
    - Farrar, Straus & Giroux (Randall Jarrell, 1914-1965), 1967., McCall Corporation (“The Elect”), 1967. Memphis State University (Film/TV rights “The Old Forest”), 1982. Sophomore Literary Festival, 1986. Klett-Cotta Verlag (German rights to A Summons To Memphis ), 1986. Chatto & Windus (United Kingdom rights to A Summons To Memphis ), 1987. Editions Gallimard (French rights to A Summons To Memphis ), 1987. Steven J. Ross (Film/TV rights to “Venus, Cupid, Folly and Time”), 1987. (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Copyright
    - “A Sentimental Journey,” “The Other Times,” “The Unforgivable,” “A Pair of Bright-Blue Eyes,” “Cousins, Family Love, Family Life, All That”, 1959., “Guests,” “Heads of Houses”, 1959. “The Girl From Forked Deer”, 1967. “Sky Line”, 1968. (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Film Adaptations
    - “The Old Forest” clipping (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Production of Plays
    - “A Stand In The Mountains” Announcements, director’s notes, stage design, clippings, schedule of events, invitation, ticket order blanks, programs, box office statements, 1968, 1971., “Tennessee Day In St. Louis” Clipping, 1958. “Three Ghost Plays” Rehearsal schedule, ticket order blanks, program, tickets, clippings, 1971. Robert Porterfield and the Barter Theatre in Abingdon, Virginia Brochure, Annual Barter Award, Congressional Record, regarding the death of Robert Porterfield, 1971. (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - “A Stand In The Mountains” Script #2 – Peter Taylor’s copy with his notes Script #10 – Actor’s copy with notes (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Readings
    - Lists of reading Engagements, 1967-1971. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Reprint Permissions
    - “At The Drugstore” – University of the South, 1963. “There” – Kenyon College, 1965. “Fiction: A Conversation With John Updike and Peter Taylor” – Sound recording, Library of Congress, 1970. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Reviews
    - The Collected Stories of Peter Taylor (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Happy Families Are All Alike (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - In The Miro District (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - A Long Fourth (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Miss Leonora When Last Seen (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - The Old Forest And Other Stories (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Presences (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - A Summons To Memphis (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - The Widows of Thornton (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - A Woman of Means (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Royalty Statements
    - Ivan Obolensky, Inc. ( Happy Families ), 1962., Harcourt, Brace & World ( Long Fourth ), 1962. Harcourt, Brace & World ( Long Fourth ), Widows of Thorton, Woman of Means ), 1962. Harcourt, Brace & World, 1962. Ivan Obolensky, Inc. ( Happy Families ), 1963. Ivan Obolensky, Inc. ( Happy Families ), 1963. Ivan Obolensky, Inc. ( Happy Families ), 1964. Farrar, Straus & Giroux ( Collected Stories ), 1970. Harper & Row ( American Short Stories 1945 ), 1972. Houghton Mifflin ( Presences ), 1973. Farrar, Straus & Co. (“ The Pilgrim Sons ”), undated. (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Lists of short stories for collection; notes; list of names and addresses of friends; directory of publishers. (Box 13, Folder 15)
- Series IV. Academic Career
  - Kenyon College
    - Tuition bills (1939/40), copy of grade list for English 2B including Taylor’s grade. (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Harvard University
    - Maps and hotel brochures for Cambridge and Boston, Bank I.D. card Exam schedules (1964/65) Medical insurance information New faculty information, 1964/65 Schedule of English classes President’s Report, 1967/68 Strike memo Visiting Committee brochures and reports (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - University of Virginia
    - Class admission card, change of grade forms, information for writers of recommendation letters (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Writers Conferences
    - Writers’ Conference, University of Utah, 1952. - Brochure, Writers’ Conference, University of Utah, 1963. - Brochures South Carolina Fiction and Poetry Conferene, 1969. – Prospectus Florida Writers’ Conference, University of Florida, 1970. – Announcement & Schedule Unidentified Workshop, 1970. – Schedules Tennessee Writers’ Conference, Vanderbilt University, 1970. – Press Release Virginia, 1971. – Brochure Boatwright Literary Festival, undated. – Announcement, Schedule, and Itinerary (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Class Lists/Grades
    - Drafts of recommendations for students. (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Recommendations Written
    - Drafts of recommendations for students. (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous
    - List of English classes and instructors, Spring 1952 (possibly University of Chicago), English Club Faculty Questionnaire Draft, re: creative writing degree requirements Draft, re: “Department’s Balch lecture series” Bibliography of folk songs Bibliography of contemporary Japanese authors List of short stories (Box 13, Folder 22)
- Series V. Biographical/Personal Papers
  - Biographical
    - Biographical questionnaire completed by Taylor in 1952., Press Release from University of North Carolina Greensboro, 1964. Copy from Who’s Who (1986/87, 1988/89) for updating. List of works written (1937-1963). (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Clippings, ca. 1943-1987. (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Interview by Barbara Davis, with Taylor’s holograph corrections, typescript draft, 1981[?] (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Interview, Paris Review, with Taylor’s holograph corrections, 1987[?] (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Interview, Paris Review, with Taylor’s holograph corrections, 1987[?] (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Military Papers, 1941 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Writings About Peter Taylor
    - Peden, William. “A Hard and Admirable Toughness: The Stories of Peter Taylor.” Hollins Critic 7 (February, 1970): 1-9. Copy signed by Peter Taylor. (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Robison, J.C. The Short Stories of Peter Taylor. Typescript of outline, preface and chapter 1, 1987. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Taylor, Martha. “Fiction Interpreted As Fact – A Study of A Long Fourth and Other Stories”, class paper, 1973. (Box 14, Folder 4)